《Fat Papa Tells Stories》
［The Goose That Laid the Golden Eggs］
There was a very lucky couple.
They had a goose that laid a golden egg every day.
Although they were already very lucky,
they soon felt that their wealth was not increasing fast enough.
Not only that,
they also thought that the goose's insides must be made of gold.
So they decided to kill it.
That way, they could get all the gold immediately.
But when they cut open the goose's belly,
they discovered that this goose was just like any other goose.
As a result, they didn't get rich overnight as they had hoped.
Nor could they continue to enjoy the daily
good fortune of getting a golden egg.
This Aesop's fable tells us
that people should know how to be content and happy, not greedy without limits.
Killing the goose that lays the golden eggs is foolish behavior.